<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book SYSTEM "lab04_book.dtd">
<?xml-stylesheet href="lab04_book.css" type="text/css"?>
<!-- Source: https://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/2852 -->
<!-- Footnotes were added by Péter Jeszenszky -->
<book>
    <author>Sir Arthur Conan Doyle</author>
    <title>The Hound of the Baskervilles</title>
    <chapter>
        <title>Mr. Sherlock Holmes</title>
        <para>Mr. Sherlock Holmes, who was usually very late in the mornings, save upon those not
            infrequent occasions when he was up all night, was seated at the breakfast table. I
            stood upon the hearth-rug and picked up the stick which our visitor had left behind him
            the night before. It was a fine, thick piece of wood, bulbous-headed, of the sort which
            is known as a “Penang lawyer.” Just under the head was a broad silver band nearly an
            inch across. “To James Mortimer, M.R.C.S.<footnote>Member of the Royal Colleges of
            Surgeons</footnote>, from his friends of the C.C.H.<footnote>Charing Cross Hospital</footnote>,”
            was engraved upon it, with the date “1884.” It was just such a stick as the
            old-fashioned family practitioner used to carry—dignified, solid, and reassuring.</para>
        <para>“Well, Watson, what do you make of it?”</para>
        <para>Holmes was sitting with his back to me, and I had given him no sign of my occupation.</para>
        <para>“How did you know what I was doing? I believe you have eyes in the back of your head.”</para>
        <para>“I have, at least, a well-polished, silver-plated coffee-pot in front of me,” said he.
            “But, tell me, Watson, what do you make of our visitor’s stick? Since we have been so
            unfortunate as to miss him and have no notion of his errand, this accidental souvenir
            becomes of importance. Let me hear you reconstruct the man by an examination of it.”</para>
        <para>“I think,” said I, following as far as I could the methods of my companion, “that Dr.
            Mortimer is a successful, elderly medical man, well-esteemed since those who know him
            give him this mark of their appreciation.”</para>
        <para>“Good!” said Holmes. “Excellent!”</para>
        <para>“I think also that the probability is in favour of his being a country practitioner
            who does a great deal of his visiting on foot.”</para>
        <!-- ... -->
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <title>The Curse of the Baskervilles</title>
        <para>“I have in my pocket a manuscript,” said Dr. James Mortimer.</para>
        <para>“I observed it as you entered the room,” said Holmes.</para>
        <para>“It is an old manuscript.”</para>
        <para>“Early eighteenth century, unless it is a forgery.”</para>
        <para>“How can you say that, sir?”</para>
        <para>“You have presented an inch or two of it to my examination all the time that you have
            been talking. It would be a poor expert who could not give the date of a document within
            a decade or so. You may possibly have read my little monograph upon the subject. I put
            that at 1730.”</para>
        <para>“The exact date is 1742.” Dr. Mortimer drew it from his breast-pocket. “This family
            paper was committed to my care by Sir Charles Baskerville, whose sudden and tragic death
            some three months ago created so much excitement in Devonshire<footnote>Former name of
            Devon, a county of England</footnote>. I may say that I was his personal friend as well
            as his medical attendant. He was a strong-minded man, sir, shrewd, practical, and as
            unimaginative as I am myself. Yet he took this document very seriously, and his mind was
            prepared for just such an end as did eventually overtake him.”</para>
        <!-- ... -->
    </chapter>
    <!-- ... -->
</book>